<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events | NSF Project</title>
    <link>/event/</link>
      <atom:link href="/event/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Events</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2024 VCBSL, Wichita State University</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/media/logo_hu06375921a11c4bfd943c316038ab1a00_475295_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Events</title>
      <link>/event/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding and Mitigating Demographic Bias in Biometric Systems(UMDBB)</title>
      <link>/event/umdbb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/event/umdbb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;goals-and-technical-issues-addressed&#34;&gt;Goals and Technical Issues addressed&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To address significant advances in the field of fairness and bias in AI with an application to biometrics systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To provide a common forum for applied and academic researchers to exchange ideas on metrics and methods for evaluating and mitigating demographic effects in biometric performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To address the disconnect between the work done by government, academicians, and industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;topics-covered&#34;&gt;Topics Covered&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Statistical modeling of the demographic bias of the biometric systems across age, gender, and race in different image spectrums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theoretical explanation and nomenclature regarding demographic effects in biometric systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Modeling the compound impact of covariates such as lighting variations, make-up, pose, etc., in differential accuracy of the biometric systems across demographic variations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explainable AI techniques to understand the cause of demographic variations in biometric systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluation of bias of speaker recognition system, and other behavioral biometrics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Biological origins of demographic effects on physical and behavioral biometric traits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bias mitigation techniques that offer the best trade-off between accuracy and bias.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bias mitigation techniques in the absence of demographic variables.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Techniques on enhancing privacy and fairness of the biometric surveillance system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Evaluation of bias of biometric data manipulation detection algorithms across demographics.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Investigation of novel bias-free biometric modalities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
